Dr. Sidney Isenberg Collection on Carson McCullers WLU.Coll.0097
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Dr. Sidney Isenberg Collection on Carson McCullers
Inclusive 1948-1971
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
McCullers, Carson
Isenberg, Sidney
Carr, Virginia Spencer
Cleckley, Hervey M. (Hervey Milton)
WLU.Coll.0097
.2 Linear Feet
Online Access
View this collection online via W&L's Digital Archive
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dr. Sidney Isenberg.
Biographical / Historical
Lula Carson McCullers was a famous American author.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes 67 items collected by Dr. Sidney Isenberg, a member of the Class of 1942, Washington and Lee University, from his friendship with Carson McCullers, including letters to him from McCullers, from other people about her, an inscribed poem, and memorabilia.
Correspondence; Poetry; Women authors; Williams, Tennessee
- Control folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence (McCullers & Sydney Isenberg), March 9, 1948 - May 6, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-03-09 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-04-13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-04-14 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-05-06 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence (McCullers & Sydney Isenberg), May 12, 1948 - Nov. 24, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-05-12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-05-26 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-08-11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-09-28 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-11-24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence (McCullers & Sydney Isenberg), Dec. 1, 1948 - Oct. 6, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-12-01 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1949-02-21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1950-09-02 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1950-10-03 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1952-04-30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1952-10-06 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence (McCullers) Typed transcripts, 1948 - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Telegrams (McCullers to Sydney Isenberg), April 9, 1948 - Sept. 1, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-04-09 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-05-16 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1950-10-10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1950-10-25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1953-11-26 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1953-12-27 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1954-09-01 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carson McCullers to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1962-11-04 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence (Virginia S. Carr to Sidney Isenberg), 1970 - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanley Lewis to Virginia Spencer Carr, 1970-06-23 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Spencer Carr to Dr. H. M. Cleckley, 1970-09-28 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dr. Hervey Cleckley to Dr. Virginia Spencer Carr, 1970-10-05 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Spencer Carr to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1970-11-16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Spencer Carr to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1970-12-08 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Spencer Carr to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1970-12-24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Spencer Carr to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1971-01-27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Spencer Carr to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1971-01-31 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Spencer Carr to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1971-03-12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Interview questions for Dr. Sidney Isenberg, N. D. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Carson McCullers to [David], 1941-07-19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence (Hervey Cleckley to Sidney Isenberg), 1948 - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Hervey Cleckley to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-04-02 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Hervey Cleckley to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1948-05-31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Hervey Cleckley to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1950-10-29 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence (Margarita Smith to Sidney Isenberg), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Rita Smith to Dr. Sidney Isenberg, 1968-05-29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- The Dual Angel (inscribed copy), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript: The Dual Angel: A Meditation on Origin and Choice, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Memorabilia, N. D. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Carson McCullers to the Editor about the Columbus [Georgia] Public Library, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Memorabilia (Mademoiselle), 1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Memorabilia (Member of the Wedding), N. D. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Memorabilia (Article on Tennessee Williams), N. D. (Box 1, Folder 14)